Lucien: You will encounter your luckiest day of the year this month.
Lucien: .....When you feel that a certain action needs extra good luck and support, please heed the voice of your heart and enjoy the energy of the universe.
Withdrawing his gaze from the phone screen, Lucien looks toward me with a smile.
Lucien: Looks like our answers are the same.
MC: …Really? So magical!¹
I delightfully hold my phone and move closer. The two connected screens clearly display the same deck of cards with the same guiding words.
Lately, several colleagues at the company have been keen on looking into metaphysics, so I pulled Lucien along to have some fun after dinner today.
Even though I know I should regard public fortune-telling with rationality, the "mutual understanding" born out of random probability still brings a sweet delight to my heart.
I shift into a more comfortable position and nestle up to his side, even shaking my head in satisfaction.
Lucien: Does this make you so happy?
MC: Because it's a coincidence, it's very easy for this kind of just-right sense of destiny to hit you right in the heart~
Lucien: Then I'd rather understand it this way. It's because we're becoming more and more alike now that we've made the same choice.
Lucien: Rather than fate's arrangement, I'd rather attribute it to you.
MC: Professor Xu's 'theory' indeed sounds more reasonable, I especially resonate with it~
I smile as I rest my head against his shoulder, my fingertip unconsciously tapping at the screen.
MC: But no matter how I look at it, this set of cards is just too perfect. It kinda feels like I've already been hit by good luck, and that just makes me look forward to it even more.
Lucien lets out a thoughtful 'mm', but it doesn’t feel like a response. I turn my head in puzzlement, seeing him looking back at the text on the screen as if he's scrutinizing it.
I just made a casual remark, this person wouldn't actually be seriously studying it now, would he?
MC: Lucien, I...
A sudden kiss completely devours the words I haven't yet spoken.
His broad palm cradles the back of my head, pulling my lost balance back into his arms.
Our pressed skin stirs up a faint, restless heat, and his unbroken kisses surge like the tide, leaving me only fleeting moments to catch my breath.
It isn't until it suddenly starts raining outside, its soft patter mixing with the hum of the air conditioner, that he finally puts some distance between us.
Rainwater covers the condensation on the windows once again, a scene that seems to repeat countless times throughout this rainy season.
As if he notices that I am about to 'call him out'², Lucien innocently blinks his eyes and taps on the screen with righteous confidence, bringing up the previous page—
"Don't be stingy in expressing your love to your partner."
Lucien: I just wanted to experience the feeling of being struck by good luck too.
MC: Pfft, now you're the one getting superstitious.
Lucien: After all, I also have things I want to look forward to.
As we chat, the phone screen dims, and only the heart-shaped lamp on the bookshelf remains lit, blending the two of us curled up on the sofa into its dreamy, romantic glow.
//Trivia, The heart-shaped lamp is their gift from 7th anniversary!//
As the rain beats noisily, I suddenly feel like teasing him and brush my foot lightly against his.
MC: But Professor Xu, we're facing a real-world problem right now.
MC: According to the card reading, to enjoy the energy of the universe, we need to experience nature and soak up plenty of sunshine.
MC: But the weather forecast says it’ll be rainy in Loveland City for the next few weeks, so what can we do?
Lucien: Maybe we could make a few teru teru bozu³ and hang them up?
When he finishes speaking, he starts laughing first, which makes me laugh too as I cup his face in my hands and gently knead it.
MC: It’s over. All the rationality and logic of my great scientist have slipped away. That won't do, I've got to catch them and bring them back.
Lucien: Just let them go.
Lucien takes the opportunity to hold my hand and pulls me down onto the sofa, wrapping me fully in his embrace.
Lucien: Right now, all I want is to have a sweet dream with you.
As he speaks, he tightens his arms around me, making me nestle my head even more snugly against his chest.
In my haze, I hear Lucien speak.
Lucien: MC, your anticipation won’t be in vain.
Lucien: Though I don't know what exactly will happen then, I believe the entire universe will come to help you.
Lucien: And when that time comes, do remember to give me good luck and support too.
[¹] 神奇 (shén qí) is the key term of this story; it is a two-character compound word made up of two words: 神 (shén - literally "god" or "divine”) and 奇 (qí- literally "strange," "rare," "unusual”). It refers not just to unexpected phenomena, but to events and maybe even presence that feel uncannily perfect, fated, or deeply moving, almost as if the universe has ✨aligned✨ just for you.
In this translation, I will translate 神奇 as words like magical, wondrous, or miraculous, depending on the context, so if you see those words please remember its thematic significance!
[²] The idiom used for that description is 兴师问罪 (xīng shī wèn zuì), which literally means "to mobilize troops to question a crime." 兴师 refers to raising an army, while 问罪 means to hold someone accountable for wrongdoing.
Compared to just accusing sb, it's more dramatic and has that sense of righteous authority LOL. Here, it's used playfully as she’s about to pretend to make a big deal and confront Lucien for kissing her without warning~
[³] "Teru teru bozu" (てるてる坊主) or known in Chinese as 晴天娃娃 (qíng tiān wá wa-literally means clear sky/sunny day doll) is a small handmade doll crafted from white cloth or paper and hung by windows to pray for sunny skies.
For someone like Lucien, who typically relies on data and logic, his willingness to hang some not only shows the care he puts into preparing even the smallest details beyond his rationality for her happiness, but also reveals a growing, softer side of him that's learning to embrace wonder and hope no matter how irrational it may seem 🥺
Before we get to Exclusive Radio, it’s important to know that person he is speaking to in Because of Love Exclusive Radio is the same Zeng Shu (曾抒) from last year's summer 海不再遥远 SP (The Sea No Longer Far Away/Seaside at Last SP) Exclusive Radio (You can check the link of the date in Pre-Kite SP Guide!)
Though in the official localization, there was a mistranslation where Lucien asks him, "Aren't you a recent graduate?", whereas in the original, Xu Mo actually said that Professor Zeng isn't a recent graduate, which is why he was confused about why such a senior professor with extensive experience would suddenly want to withdraw from the project.
As for now, from the CN Server 2024 100 Days Countdown Event, Xu Mo's diary revealed that he eventually returned to the project. Anyway, since the official localization refers to him as Joshua, I’ll stick with that naming convention. Similar to how I translate Xu Mo as Lucien Xu in my own translation, I’ll translate his name into Joshua Zeng.
[Lucien] Professor Zeng? Is something the matter?
[Joshua] My apologies for disturbing your rest.
[Joshua] I called because I have some good news to share with you.
[Joshua] First, the project I've been working on made a major breakthrough today. I believe the following steps will go much more smoothly.
[Lucien] That's great. Everyone must be really happy, right?
[Joshua] Yes, we were even afraid it might be a false reading, so we specifically ran multiple rounds of cross-verification.
[Joshua] We've been running calculations since midnight, and it’s only now that we’re certain that there's no issue.
[Joshua] Looking back now, I realize it really has been a long time since this project was first launched…
[Lucien] Mm, this is the project you brought into my lab.
[Lucien] Just counting the time at the Bioscience Research Center, it's been about three years.
[Lucien] If we factor in the time you spent doing independent research beforehand, it's roughly been… about seven years?
[Joshua] Seven years and eight months.⁴
[Joshua] There was a time I thought I might have to wait a few more years before I could see any progress in the experiment.
[Joshua] It seems I'm still quite lucky after all.
[Lucien] Congratulations to you.
[Joshua] Thank you for your congratulations. After all, maybe in a few more years, we’ll be able to publish papers under the name of the Bioscience Research Institute!
[Joshua] In any case, let's organize the data again.
[Joshua] When you come to the research center next week, we will discuss the specifics in more detail.
[Lucien] Alright. If there's no rush over the next few days, let the researchers in the team take some appropriate time off as well.⁵
[Lucien] Everyone has been working hard lately.
[Joshua] Will do. I noticed that while we were waiting for the data just now, a few of the young folks were already planning to go see the sea.
[Lucien] Then I'll be waiting to approve everyone’s leave applications.
[Lucien] But you said "some" good news just now. Is there any other good news?
[Joshua] So here's the thing. Didn't you submit two papers?
[Joshua] I got the news today that both papers were accepted.
[Lucien] Hm? I thought the reviewers would raise a few more rounds of feedback.
[Joshua] Yes. So as soon as the news came in today, Xiao Luo was overjoyed; he even asked if I wanted to go with him to fulfill his vow.⁶
[Joshua] I don't have the energy to run around with him, and I'm not much of a believer in that sort of thing…
[Joshua] Still, today really is worthy of being called a 'lucky day.'
[Lucien] Lucky day…
[Joshua] What did you say just now?
[Lucien] Ah, it's nothing.
[Lucien] It's just that I think people occasionally do need a little bit of good luck.
[Joshua] After all, most of the time, aren't our preparations and efforts precisely about waiting for that tiny bit of luck to come knocking?
[Lucien] Then it seems today is the day luck comes knocking.
[Joshua] Sure is!
[Joshua] Oh, and also, we're planning to have dinner together next Wednesday to celebrate.
[Joshua] If you have time, feel free to bring your significant other with you.⁷
[Lucien] Alright, I'll ask her about it later.
[Joshua] Then I won't bother you any further.
[Joshua] Wish you a pleasant weekend. Goodbye.
[⁴] By July 2025, when the Kite SP card was released on the CN server, “seven years and eight months” is exactly how long the game has been out since the server’s initial launch, so it also marks seven years and eight months since we first met Lucien according to the in-game timeline,
This little detail makes it feel as if this date had been planned from the very beginning ;-; or at the very least, it's a touching callback to the long road we've shared and how we've finally arrived at this point together🥲 Just as he said in the card’s line: "When we arrived, we walked a long way to get here, so there's still a long way to go." It’s been a long road, and there’s still a long way ahead~
[⁵] Aww, I love it when growth from earlier stories carries over and shows up in later ones. Look at this guy’s development compared to 海不再遥远 SP (The Sea No Longer Far Away/Seaside at Last SP).
He went from someone who didn’t understand the value of rest (for himself or others), to someone who not only understands it now but even suggests it for his team🥺
[⁶] If you ask a god for help or make a wish to them, you're expected to return to that god's temple or statue to express your thanks once the wish comes true. This act is called 还愿 (huán yuàn), which means fulfilling a vow or repaying a spiritual promise.
[⁷] While 家属 (jiā shǔ) literally means family member, it's different from 家人 (jiā rén) as 家属 (jiā shǔ) often implies a legal or formally recognized familial relationship, someone legally acknowledged as part of their household, such as a spouse or dependent listed in official records.
That said, it's vague enough in spoken Chinese to refer to a long-term, committed romantic partner. "Significant other" is the best translation here because it captures both the formal implication and the romantic intent
(still, if you introduce someone as your 家属, people will likely assume you're cohabiting or married, or soon to be)
The air after the rain carries a touch of dampness, overlaying the lush greenery with gentle hues.
I steal a glance at Lucien beside me. He gazes calmly into the distance, but the relaxed curve of his brows and eyes quietly gives away the particularly good mood he's in.
My heart suddenly softens, as if delicate ripples spread over its innermost core, making it feel both warm and ticklish.
An hour ago, I received a call from Lucien saying he'd pick me up, and then he drove me to a park on the outskirts of Loveland City.
Lucien didn't explain much on the way. He didn't say whether he happened to be passing by or came on purpose, only mentioning casually that there was a place he wanted to go.
But I'm vaguely certain that this probably isn't a spur-of-the-moment act.
Be it his unintentional sigh at a red light or the slight acceleration of the car, all of it told me he was racing against time.
The world flowed between clarity and blur with the sweep of the windshield wipers. My curiosity gradually coalesced into anticipation.
I hope whatever he's so urgently trying to do will come true.
As the car came down from the overpass, layers of green flooded into my view. In a trance, it felt as if I could hear nature breathing.
I think I know what Lucien is going to do.
As if to confirm the somewhat vague guess lingering in my heart, the rain stops five minutes after we park the car and walk into the park.
The coincidence guided by invisible hands feels especially romantic, and the instigator, too, seems satisfied with this outcome, making me unable to resist curling the corners of my lips.
MC: This almighty professor can even control the weather now.
Lucien: If I want to reach that level, I'm afraid I still need to make further efforts.
Lucien: But winning the race against the clouds does make me happy.
He speaks frankly, the tail end of his tone brisk, with even a hint of childlike satisfaction as he gently rubs my fingertips.
Seeing him like this, all I feel is fondness, and I feel happy too.
So I simply don't want to ask or to probe how he has done all of this.
It doesn't matter whether he's using scientific theory to run simulations and make predictions, using some powerful Evol, or really making a teru teru bozu in secret.
This brief period of clear sky that he has cherishingly placed in my hands is the only thing that matters.
Thinking this, I firmly clasp his hand.
MC: So it turns out my 'universe' is right here. Then I have to hold on tight and enjoy the energy he brings.
Lucien: Is it that exaggerated? Then I can't help but feel proud.
MC: It absolutely isn't an exaggeration, I'm just really happy.
Lucien: Being the reason for your happiness is the best thing that could happen to me.
Lucien: Since the weather is so nice, let's walk a bit more.
Sunshine streams through the gaps in the heavy clouds. Yet, I feel an inexplicable profound fullness, as if I’ve been thoroughly bathed by the sun.
The fresh fragrance of grass brushes past my face, mingling with the scent on Lucien’s body. As it flows along our interlocked palms, it feels as though I’ve also been dyed with the same scent.
We just keep chatting like this as we circle around the park in a big loop. It’s only when we reach the far end opposite the entrance that the rain starts to fall again in a fine, steady drizzle.
While considering whether to have dinner nearby and wait until the evening rush hour ends before slowly heading home, two slightly hurried footsteps suddenly emerge through the patter of rain.
I reflexively look toward the sound and see two red figures swaying into view, like vermilion bleeding through a patch of mist.
A couple dressed in wedding attire walks briskly past us, arm in arm under an oil-paper umbrella, and enters an inconspicuous stone-step path off to the side.
Despite their hasty steps and the way their fragmented conversation dissolves into the rain, I always feel as if I can see their smiling faces and hear their beautiful prayers.
In that fleeting moment of trance, it feels as if two similar figures cross time and overlap before my eyes.
I belatedly withdraw my gaze, turn my head, and notice that Lucien's line of sight also stops at the end of the verdant expanse.
Lucien: Looks like… we've walked to the vicinity of the Yue Lao Temple (Matchmaker Temple).⁸
Lucien: It's just that we usually take the main road over there.
Following the direction of his finger, I take a closer look. At last, I catch a glimpse of something familiar and catch a faint whiff of sandalwood, dampened by the summer rain.
Lucien: The temple should still be open at this hour. Want to take a walk around?
MC: Eh?
Lucien: I think a certain young lady would like this kind of coincidence.
That pair of beautiful brows and eyes curves up slightly; the way he says this sentence makes it feel more like an invitation.
MC: Mm, I like it.
MC: But it’s not just the coincidence that I like.
I smile as I extend my pinky and hook it around his fingertip.
MC: Maybe Old Man Yue Lao missed us, so he guided us along this invisible red thread and brought us here.
There aren’t many visitors on rainy days. After lining up to make an incense offering and pay respects to the Matchmaker God, we find a pavilion and sit down.
Dense drizzle trails along the edge of the eaves and drips onto the stone steps, while bronze bells hanging from the pavilion corridor seem suspended in ethereal silence.
Time slows down. In the distance, blue-gray smoke merges into the rain mist, casting a hazy shadow beneath the pale daylight.
I sit side by side with Lucien, listening to the rain and watching the little orange cat sleeping soundly in the corner.
MC: I wonder what the kitten is dreaming about.
Lucien: Maybe it's chasing a butterfly.
As if it hears the humans talking, the little cat suddenly twitches its ears. Then it shifts its position, squints its eyes comfortably, stretches out its paws, and sprawls its belly open.
Lucien: Looks like it caught it.
While speaking, he naturally interlocks his fingers with mine, making my eyes curve in fond amusement.
A branch of the peach tree in the backyard peeks into view. The wind stirs the red silk ribbons at its tip. Though they make no noise, I seem to hear countless beautiful and romantic sounds.
MC: Lucien.
A sudden, slightly out-of-the-blue question comes to mind, and I gently scratch his palm.
MC: Do you think the red ribbons we tied to the tree before are still there?⁹
As if not expecting me to ask this, he hesitates for a few seconds before speaking.
Lucien: I'm curious too. Let's go, who knows what kind of answer the world will give us.
The peach tree is as tall as the one in my memory. It gently holds up countless red ribbons, overlooking these stories and participating in their happening.
There are people closing their eyes and devoutly making wishes. Some are tiptoeing toward the tips of the branches to tie red ribbons, and others are solemnly putting pen to paper at the nearby wish-writing table.
Time moves forward in silence, giving birth to countless changes, yet it also seems to leave behind some things that never change.
How strange, I've clearly been to the Matchmaker Temple several times before, but standing under the tree like this, it feels like it was already a long time ago.
I can't explain why it's today of all days, perhaps I simply want to take a look.
The peach tree, along its swaying shadows, still sheds unceasing water droplets. They glide along the ribbons, falling one after another as though in reply.
The rain has stopped again without our noticing. Fluttering ribbons replace sunset light buried in the clouds, lifting a heart-stirring flush of red.
Pulling Lucien along, I tilt my head up and circle the tree back and forth, my whole vision filled with swaying red.
Vivid red, hazy red, faded red—these are the heart-pounding colors on lovers' cheeks as they offer prayers and wishes.
After looking for a long time, it feels as though an afterimage has been seared onto my retina. I rub my eyes, and when I turn my head, I bump into a gaze that’s been fixed on me the whole time.
I feel embarrassed under his stare and reach out to poke the tip of his nose.
MC: Do you think I'm being a bit childish?
Lucien: Of course not.
Lucien: I was also seriously looking just now. It's just that...
He leans down, pressing close to my ear, and whispers.
Lucien: The elderly gentleman at the wish-writing desk seems to have taken us for strange folks. He's been glancing our way on and off several times.
Lucien: Honestly, I was just thinking about how I should explain to him if he got really curious and came over to us.
I blink and peek out from beside Lucien. Sure enough, I see the old gentleman he mentioned watching us with a cautious look on his face.
Imagining how we must look to others, I smile embarrassedly.
MC: Let's just say we're making a TV show and doing on-site research? Or maybe gathering material?
Lucien: Do we really need such a formal reason?
Lucien: I rather think the Matchmaker God would prefer our most genuine intentions.
Lucien smiles as he tucks a loose strand of my hair behind my ear.
Lucien: My beloved has a heart that is both pure and romantic. She wishes to take hold once more of the happiness and destined bond that belong to us.…¹⁰
Lucien: And I hope her wish will be fulfilled.
His voice is not loud, yet it carries a certain weight of cherishing care and heartfelt earnestness. Heavily it lands upon my heart, slowing and magnifying everything.
Thump-thump—a sound.
Thump-thump—another follows close behind.
I instinctively look back into those deep eyes and see all the colors in the world merging within them. Even the swaying, flowing red is wholly dyed in his color.
Through those eyes, I seem to have found what I have been searching for all along.
⁸: It’s the same Matchmaker Temple they visited years ago in 不负相思意 SP (Bound by Love SP) Mind Quest. This temple is dedicated to Yue Lao (月老), also known as the Old Man Under the Moon, a deity in Chinese folklore who presides over love and marriage.
The myth of the red thread of fate originates from him. He is said to connect destined couples with an invisible red thread, binding their fates together. Though the thread may stretch, tangle, or twist, it is said to never break, symbolizing a bond that defies time, distance, obstacles, and even death~
In temple tradition, couples tie red silk ribbons onto sacred trees, symbolizing the red thread of fate used by Yue Lao to bind destined lovers. This act is a prayer for eternal union and divine blessing. Lucien and MC follow this custom at the Matchmaker Temple in 不负相思意 SP (Bound by Love SP) Mind Quest.
In traditional belief, when two people tie their red silk ribbons together on a sacred tree, it signifies “以树为媒，天地作证” — taking the tree as matchmaker, with heaven and earth as witnesses to their union. This transforms their simple act of tying ribbons into a sacred vow, witnessed by the universe and divine worlds.
¹⁰ : The original line is 我的爱人有一颗纯粹又浪漫的心,她想回握住一份属于我们的幸福和缘分...…There are three terms that I want to highlight: 我的爱人 (wǒ de àirén), 幸福 (xìng fú) , and 缘分 (yuán fèn)
我的爱人 (wǒ de àirén) literally means “my loved person”/“the one I love” (我的 = my/mine; 爱人 = love + person). From the 1950s to the 1990s in Mainland China, 爱人 was the common word for spouse.
Today, it may sound somewhat old-fashioned and sentimental in daily speech, but it still conveys a long-term commitment, carrying the sense of 'the person I'll love for my whole life.'
It can be translated as 'my beloved' in emotional contexts, but if you use it to introduce your partner (as Lucien does in other dates), people will assume you mean a spouse or at least a lifelong partner.
幸福 (xìng fú) is more than just “happiness.” Unlike 高兴 or 开心, which describe passing moods, 幸福 refers to a deep, lasting sense of fulfillment, often tied to love, family, and emotional well-being.
So the 'happiness' that MC wishes for leans closer to 'a blessed, fulfilling, and content life' rather than a temporary happiness.
缘分 (yuán fèn) is a concept rooted in a synthesis of Buddhist, Daoist, and Confucian thought. It refers to a predestined affinity that brings people together, yet also implies personal effort to maintain and deepen that bond.
It consists of 缘 (yuán)— the karmic condition or circumstantial force that allows people to cross paths; and 分 (fèn)—which signifies voluntary effort, personal choice, or one's 'share' of the relationship.
Unlike the passive Western notion of 'fate', yuánfèn encompasses both cosmic serendipity and human agency. I think TL it as 'destined bond' better captures its meaning: a relationship brought forth by unseen forces, but sustained through mutual intention and care.
Even though he had already sat down in the driver's seat, Lucien still couldn't help but take another glance at the tablet screen before starting the car.
The tablet had been remotely connected to the computer in the laboratory and was currently transmitting radar echoes, short-term forecasts, and various meteorological data to him in real-time.
He specifically applied for temporary access from the meteorological research department, obtained partial data, and used it in combination with the Meteorological Administration’s technology to create a simple climate simulation model.
Considering that the closer it is to the target time, the more accurate the weather forecast becomes, he further increased the frequency of data refresh.
In fact, Lucien's goal was simple: to do everything possible to ensure he could truly 'capture' that brief window of clear sky during this extended rainy season.
That way, he could naturally share what felt like a destined bit of 'good luck' with her.
But when it came down to it, his 'Sunny-Weather Capture Plan' had actually been in effect for three or four days.
The last time he predicted the rain would stop, he had just gotten ready to head out when the weather suddenly turned against him, and the plan had to be called off.
The time before that, he had caught a window between rain clouds, but was unfortunately held up by an unexpected meeting.
If he missed the chance again this time, the next brief spell of sunshine wouldn’t arrive until the following week.
He had to admit, tailoring luck in a field he wasn't very familiar with turned out to be a bit more troublesome than he had imagined.
The lingering drizzle wouldn't stop, and of all times, a red light brought him to a halt again.
After a fleeting glance at the tablet and confirming the model again, Lucien's eyes drifted toward the low-hanging clouds, and he let out a soft sigh.
Lucien: ...I should still make it in time.
He had always considered himself fairly patient, yet now, he found himself lightly tapping the steering wheel again and again.
The image of the girl’s smiling eyes flashed through his mind, followed by the plans he had prepared.
Lucien tried to tell himself that even if he didn't make it in time for the sunny weather, it didn’t matter. He had made thorough preparations anyway—
If it still rained, there was an umbrella with a jellyfish pattern in the trunk, which would most likely make her light up with delighted surprise.¹¹
Or he could simply turn the car around and take her to the plum garden he had booked to taste the freshly brewed plum wine.¹²
If all else failed… he could still pretend that he merely happened to be passing by because of some coincidence.
He would just drive her home, listen as she shared glimpses of her workday, and then, together, choose a movie suited for a rainy day.
He had crafted every possible contingency plan; each one certain to please her. But...
Lucien: If only the sky would clear up for a little while.
Lucien: Just a brief moment would be enough.
When it comes to things related to her, he always wants to be a little greedier.
Even this elusive luck, he longs to grasp it in his hands, polish it into a glittering gift with his heartfelt intentions, delicately adorn it with surprises, wrap it all up, and hold it out before her eyes.¹³
And receive in return her eyes instantly lighting up as she beams and throws herself into his embrace.
He smiled and sighed, not knowing whether this was the hundredth time he had gazed at his tablet during this stretch of time that was neither long nor short.
The model's predicted result remains unchanged; it still indicates that the overcast rain will briefly pause in an hour and a half.
This time, he didn't wait any longer. He lit up his phone and dialed her number.
Lucien: It's me. Is the shoot going well?
Lucien: Actually, I'm currently on my way to the set. I'll be there in a bit…
The green light turned on, and Lucien stepped on the accelerator again, moving forward along the lane.
Heading toward the clear sky belonging to him.
¹¹: This is more of a trivia than an serious insight, I just find it really cute that jellyfish is one of the animals associated with him~ It appear as… ahem… euphemistic imagery during 2023 his flower banner.
They also appear in the 2022 Lovepro X Shining Nikki Collab, his 2024 White Day R karma, and the 2023 summer event, where he purchased three Moon Jellyfish for their summer café. It is also creatively used again in euphemistic writing, as they do ‘this and that’ in the said café.
¹²: The plum wine is not just a sweet random idea and rather a direct callback to 山野之约 (Wilderness Date), the one date where they pick green plums and taste sweet, spicy, and sour homemade plum wine in the summer of 2021 🥺
Probably just a small detail, but I want to point it out, because it makes it feel like every moment from the past matters, like all those memories, no matter how small they seem, shape who he is today, and how he continues to treasure them.
¹³: The way that line strongly echoes what MC said back in Sweet Dream Date (which, in the CN server, takes place in summer 2024) makes me want to cry (இ﹏இ`｡) He’s really someone who pays such tender attention, quietly cherishing every little fragment of her, even things that she doesn't say,
polishing them with his heart then treasures them, and present them back to his beloved as if the universe itself had a hand in them. Every gift from him carries special meaning, and they are the very proof of his sincerest love for her🥺
MC: You saw them too, right? Those are precisely the red ribbons we tied back then!
MC: I remember we tied one ribbon first, then tied the other one on top of it. That's why the knot looks like that… Anyway, I'm sure of it.
MC: I never expected that they had neither been routinely cleared away nor worn down by wind and rain, but instead still hang there on the tree, perfectly intact…
MC: ...It's truly wondrous.
On our way back from the Matchmaker Temple, I'm still chattering away, relishing what just happened.¹⁴
The last wash of sunset glow tints the horizon a beautiful pinkish purple, its hue soaking into the damp stone steps.
Lucien doesn't say a word the whole time, just smiles as he listens to me.
Looking at those smiling eyes, I clear my throat a little, feeling slightly embarrassed.
MC: Alright, I admit that after years of absorbing your influence by osmosis, I've become a bit more realistic and pragmatic.
MC: But we've experienced so many miraculous moments over the past two days… Like we're being watched over with fondness and blessed by grace. It's both wondrous and blissful.
MC: So I can't help but feel deeply moved.
Lucien: I know. That's why I'm relishing it too.
MC: Liar, that smile of yours looks like you’re teasing me.
Lucien: Would I really be that mean?
Lucien: I honestly just think you're utterly endearing. The world looks beautiful and full of wonder when seen through your eyes.
Lucien: It responded to your hopes and brought us miracles.
The evening breeze blows softly, and the world melts into a rustling expanse of tender hue.
Lucien: And ever since being with you, I keep encountering many illogical, low-probability events that call to be pursued and explored.
Lucien: Your existence has made me accustomed to miracles happening naturally.
Lucien: Isn't this miraculous?
Rather than a question, it feels more like he's marveling.
How could I not be lucky too—to be the curiosity of the one who's curious about the world, to be the exploration he longs to explore.
I can't help but rise onto my tiptoes and plant a soft peck at the corner of his lips.
MC: Alright, alright, I can't out-argue you. I give up.¹⁵
Lucien: That won't do.
He leans in, and his warm breath falls upon my squinting eyes and the tip of my nose, before finally coming to rest at the edge of my lips.
Lucien: Just let me be the one to admit defeat.¹⁶
The lights along the stone-step path light up one by one; the already long mountain trail grows slower beneath our pace, as if we tacitly wish to prolong this moment.
I gently shake our clasped hands.
MC: Speaking of which, have you still gone to the Matchmaker Temple by yourself again since then?¹⁷
//⚠️'Since then' here does not refer to the 'Bound by Love' SP Mind Quest. Please refer to the [Translation Notes and Insights] for context. This clarification is critical as the date being referenced may not be released on the EN server for quite some time.⚠️//
Lucien: No, I haven't. But I did visit Grandma Wen a while ago; she can vouch for that.
MC: Pfft, I never said I didn't believe you.
Seeing him explain so seriously, I can't help but laugh.
MC: Lucien, let's visit the temple together from now on.¹⁸
Lucien: Okay.
Lucien agrees almost without hesitation.
He doesn't ask me the reason, and only responds with an earnestness that makes it more of a promise than a reply.
I actually can't explain exactly what I'm thinking in this moment, or why I'd make a promise about something that doesn't seem to need promising at all.
Perhaps it's just because I'm walking with him like this that I unintentionally begin to freely imagine many distant things.
They all will happen naturally on some day in the future.
Somehow, I suddenly remember that promise.
It always lies deep in my memories, silent and still, yet deafening whenever I recall it.
I instinctively look toward Lucien.
When the weather is good, let's go fly a kite.
I think about it, and the memory alone makes my heart clamor.
The evening breeze brushes past the shrubs, sweeps over the hem of my skirt, and stirs the ends of Lucien's hair.
Perhaps I'm too deeply lost in thought; it's only when that profound gaze looks back at me that I sheepishly avert my eyes.
MC: What is it?
A soft chuckle falls on my ear, and Lucien smiles as he boops my nose.
Lucien: I admit it. I really like it when you look at me like this. In fact, I don't want to interrupt this moment either.
MC: Humph, and yet you still interrupted me?
I figure he's probably teasing me again, so I just go along with what he says. But to my surprise, he ends up looking even more innocent.
Lucien: What if I tell you I have a good reason?
Lucien: There's a beautiful scene I don't want you to miss. Or rather, I want to experience it together with you.
As Lucien speaks, he takes my hand and steps down a stair, guiding my gaze forward.
The next second, I can't help but widen my eyes.
MC: ...Fireflies!
Scattered luminescence flows out unceasingly from the bushes, like sprinkles of stardust adrift before our eyes.
Drifting and floating, they converge into a swaying galaxy, like a gift from the gods.
Lucien watches the girl beside him, her smile blooming and the glow of fireflies leaping into her eyes. He can't help but smile too.
In truth, he's the one who should be grateful.
Without her, he himself probably wouldn't have seen such a dreamlike and beautiful scene.
And the moment his gaze shifts away from her, the world fades back into a photographic negative needing to be refocused.
So he instinctively tightens his grip on her hand, as if this way he holds not only her joy, but his own as well.
Now, he seems to have gradually learned how to hold onto this beautiful miracle.
What he said is true: the way she's made him grow accustomed to miracles and beauty is far more miraculous than any so-called coincidence.
He quietly watches the girl, watches her gaze turn toward him, watches her eyes brim with delight.
Lucien feels love.
He inexplicably thinks of this word, even though he still cannot define it.
It’s born alongside too many emotions; it makes him unlike himself, yet through him, it allows him to become himself.
His heart throbs uncontrollably. The feeling of his chest being completely filled, just like it was at the Matchmaker Temple, comes flooding back again.
They stood side by side, gazing together at the peach tree, which was covered with red silk ribbons.
Vast expanses of green and red permeated the world, as if becoming the only two fragments of color left. For a moment, he felt as though everything had reverted to a single hue once more.
Equally monotonous, yet so different from black and white.
The colors now had warmth and were tangible to the touch, making him unable to resist closing his fingers tighter around hers.
And this warmth enveloped him as tenaciously as a miracle. He couldn’t help but keep confirming, keep turning back, always looking toward the girl by his side who had brought it all into being.
How can I tell you just how miraculous you are?
Lucien thought to himself.
She tilted her head up, searching with unblinking focus, as if she would never back down or give up no matter what.
And he knows why she is so persistent and perseverant.¹⁹
He happens to be her persistence and perseverance.
Lucien's gaze lightly swept over the others beneath the tree. Though he couldn't know what was in their hearts and minds, he genuinely sensed similar emotions.
He, too, has someone who would naturally appear in his heart at this moment.
It turns out time can roll back, like the returning surge of a rising tide.
The flower that quietly bloomed in the depths of his heart has now blossomed into a form he had never foreseen, gently and steadily cradling his abnormally pounding heart.
The fireflies illuminate her, and they also illuminate his pain and obsession.²⁰
And yet, each increment of pain feels even more like the most solid proof transmitted from his heart.
It is as if the world is tenderly opening its embrace, welcoming its clumsy child to experience and enjoy the most touching and profound beauty of life.
He softly speaks her name, grasping with his own hands a certain kind of fate that belongs only to him.
Lucien: Tomorrow… let’s go fly a kite.
I like how the story is structured so that the kite isn't something he plans in advance because of a lucky day. Heck, the kite isn't even on their minds when they first hear about it. Instead, the idea of a "lucky day" pushes them to show their dedication to each other in parallel: she insists on finding the red ribbon, while he works tirelessly to catch a fleeting patch of sunshine.
Both of them are collecting small pieces of luck for a future they can already sense but haven't yet put into words. And when persistence and chance come together, those little pieces of luck gently and naturally bring back the memory of the kite promise🥺
¹⁴: 回 (huí) means 'to return', and 味 (wèi) means 'taste'. Together, 回味 (huíwèi) literally means 'to return to the taste' and figuratively refers to savoring a past experience or emotion. What I mean by 'relishing' here is not just enjoying, but savoring in a thoughtful, gentle way like 'tasting' memories that linger.
¹⁵⁺¹⁶: MC's 投降 (tóuxiáng) is a term for formal surrender (e.g., in war). It's precisely the formality that makes its use in a daily context playful and theatrical, like declaring a dramatic defeat or waving a white flag LOL.
Lucien's 认输 (rènshū) means 'to admit defeat' and is more personal and introspective. It refers to an internal acknowledgment of loss, often after a struggle. By choosing this word, he gently rejects her theatrical gesture to instead make a sincere and vulnerable concession, acknowledging that he is the one truly overcome🥺
The phrase "since then" in MC's line refers back to the Binding Knot Date, where Grandma Wen (also the same Grandma Wen from Chapter 9 who taught MC how to make a peace knot) pulls MC aside and reveals that Lucien has visited the Matchmaker Temple alone on several occasions.
MC later confronts him about it, asking if he's encountered a problem that 'materialism' can't solve. Lucien admits he goes there to seek comfort regarding his relationship with MC, worrying that his mistakes might make her unhappy and wondering if he's not doing well enough.
A 'materialist' who goes against logic for his beloved because matters of the heart are too complex to explain through reason alone… this reflects a key stage in his character development.
This date also shows how much he pays attention even to their smallest quarrels, learning to see them as a natural part of being in a relationship. Anyway, MC's question here checks if he has resumed his habit of seeking solitary solace.
¹⁸: By asking Lucien to visit the Matchmaker Temple together from now on, MC not only breaks his pattern of carrying worries alone but also turns it into a shared promise for their road ahead.
The act itself carries cultural undertones, as visiting the temple as a couple is often tied to love and long-term commitment, which is why her thoughts naturally drift toward their future. And Lucien's simple, sincere "Okay" lands like a vow of its own, affirming her proposal🥺
¹⁹: While both 执着 (zhí zhuó) and 坚持 (jiān chí) can be translated as 'persistence', their connotations are different. 执着 (zhí zhuó) describes a state of mind, a deep, often stubborn or obsessive attachment to an idea, goal, or person. At the same time, 坚持 (jiān chí) focuses on the action of continuing to do something despite difficulties.
坚持 (jiān chí) emphasizes steadfastness, endurance, and willpower in upholding principles, habits, or plans. MC's 执着 is her profound emotional fixation on Lucien, and this feeling is what fuels her 坚持, her unwavering effort and perseverance in their relationship.
It's almost silly how they've become each other's embodiment of what defines them. Like for MC, Lucien is her persistence and perseverance; for Lucien, MC is his curiosity and quest.
²⁰: The term 沉迷 consists of two characters: 沉 (chén): 'to sink' or 'to be immersed in' and 迷 (mí): 'to be fascinated by', 'to be lost in', or 'to be obsessed with'. The literal meaning of 沉迷 is 'to sink into and become lost in a fascination'. It evokes someone willingly allowing themselves to be submerged and enchanted by something,
to the point of losing their bearings in anything else. I use obsession to translate 沉迷 because it is a good approximation, but maybe it can't fully capture the sinking (沉) feeling, like this all-consuming, overwhelming absorption in her and his love for her.
Dark blue night spills across the windshield; streetlights sweep past within sight, transforming into flowing amber on the damp road.
I can't help but sneak another glance from the corner of my eye, catching a glimpse of Lucien's calm, unchanged expression.
I had thought that after his invitation, we would go buy a kite together.
But as we pass by several malls or supermarkets that appear to sell kites along the way, he shows almost no intention of stopping the car, and there is even a trace of inexplicable silence.
Could it be that he has already quietly prepared something without my knowing?
I can't quite make sense of it, but helpless against too many indescribable emotions flooding my mind, I don't break this silence either.
Any moment now, once we turn at the next intersection, we'll be home...
Lucien: MC, we're almost home.
MC: Ah… yeah, we are. What is it?
I subconsciously hold my breath.
Lucien: Want to grab a late-night snack at that food stall nearby?
MC: …Well, okay.
I stretch the corner of my mouth into a reluctant smile and agree, then immediately feel somewhat annoyed at my undisciplined emotions getting the better of me.
Perhaps it is because tonight is one of these recent nights when the rain has rarely stopped that the food stalls are bustling at this hour. Cooking smoke mingles with the damp air, steaming up into a hazy mist.
The savory aroma of barbecue burrows into my nose, and amid the leaping charcoal fire and the clinking of glasses, it sketches a clamorous, warmly human bustle.
Lucien and I simply order some food and sit down at one of the outdoor seats.
The night's temperature sheds the day's mugginess, soft and fresh as if rinsed clean by rain.
Lucien: The weather forecast says there’s about an 80% chance of rain tomorrow.
MC: Pfft… So that's what you were looking at all along?
From those deep-set eyes, a sliver of resignation seeps out without the slightest concealment. Lucien sets down his phone, naturally peeling a shrimp and placing it into my bowl.
Lucien: Fortunately, there's still a 20% chance.
MC: [smiles softly] Why does it sound like you're cheering yourself up, Professor Xu?
Lucien: Was it that obvious? I was clearly trying to come off a bit more nonchalant.
He speaks with feigned gravity, his half-joking tone making us laugh in unison; yet I faintly sense the emotions concealed within it.
The night wind blows gently, the lamplight at the shop entrance softly melts into the puddle on the ground, forming a fuzzy-edged moon—
—as if it too illuminates the thoughts weighing on my heart.
Be it 20% or 10%; even if only a faint 1% glimmer of possibility- at this moment, I greedily hope that tomorrow can be that one luckiest day of ours.
I hope tomorrow will be good weather.²¹
After we finish dinner and return home, Lucien heads straight into the bathroom.
On this night no different from any other, it is I who finds myself a little absent-minded.
While thinking over the matter of the kite and worrying about the change in weather, I push open the bathroom door with my change of clothes in hand, just in time to see Lucien taking off his shirt.
Lucien: …..
MC: ……
MC: ...Y-you haven't showered yet? Then hurry up, okay?
I babble incoherently with awkward laughter, slam the door shut in one motion, then shake my head hard, trying to jolt my muddled mind a little clearer.
Immediately after, I hear two light knocks coming from the other side of the door.
Lucien: If you're in a hurry, I can let you go first.
Lucien: Of course. I'd also be very happy to leave this time for us to share together.
MC: Stop teasing me, just hurry up and get in!
Lucien: [chuckles] Then I'll be quick.
Soon, steam infused with the scent of body wash wafts up, and my face belatedly grows a little warm.
Hugging the clothes to my chest, I sit down on the sofa and subconsciously glance out the window again.
Maybe it's just a psychological effect, but ever since finding out the forecast, I find myself constantly paying attention to the 'weather'.
The muffled thunder from the distant horizon, the water droplets shaken loose from the tree branches by the wind, even the gurgling of water coming from the bathroom at this moment...
Each one keeps magnifying in my ears and before my eyes.
And weirdly enough, this state lingers on and off all the way until just before I fall asleep.
Listening to the steady breathing of the person beside me, I suddenly feel a bit unsure whether he's actually asleep or not.
My continuously sinking consciousness is tugged at by scattered, trivial thoughts, as if caught in an intangible tug-of-war.
I don't know how much time has passed. Amid the hazy daze, I hear the sound of raindrops falling.
²¹: The way that line is precisely the same as what MC said back in Sacred Mountain Date Official Translation🤧 These are the same emotional gesture: MC clings to a sliver of possibility despite the snow, wind, and rain with both the Golden Mountain and the flying kite being symbols of improbable fortune…
Thinking about it, their relationship is inextricably tied to luck, isn't it? From their first love token being iridescent, a symbol of (rainbow) luck, to the golden mountain, then a game in his 2024 Birthday in CN server, where it's only when he gives himself a bit of luck that he finally meets her, even if it took him 500 years.
Meeting her in the first place is perhaps his greatest stroke of 'luck' that even if it brings him pain and destruction, he accepts it not as resignation but as devoted willingness, that he'd choose it again and again, no matter the cost.
Still, it’s essential to recognize that it isn't luck alone that keeps them together. Just as Joshua/Zeng Shu's research required years of effort before that small stroke of luck arrived, Lucien insistently tries to tailor luck for her, and MC just as persistently seeks out the red ribbon they tied together years ago to hold onto their destined bond,
the story makes it clear that although luck is a theme, their meeting, their effort to keep being together through learning and understanding how to open their heart and love each other, and later the fulfillment of the kite promise are never just mere chance, but something shaped through intention, persistence, and deliberate choices that wait for a little bit of luck to come.
I’m still a bit dazed as I walk into the park.
The humming of the early morning downpour still echoes in my ears, while the lingering moisture in the air has quietly evaporated in the sunlight.
Though it's not yet noon, the blazing sunshine tears through the clouds and slants downward, spreading across the vast green shade. Like a frozen scene, only the clamorous cries of cicadas remain.
I feel my whole body heating up, and for a moment, I can't tell whether it's from the sun or from the warmth in my heart.
As I sneak a glance for the umpteenth time at the kite in Lucien's other hand, he suddenly gives my hand a slight squeeze.
Feeling caught, I hurriedly raised my other hand to fan myself.
MC: With the sun so blazing now, who would've thought it was pouring just this early morning?
Lucien narrows his eyes slightly, a meaningful smile playing on his lips.
Lucien: It turns out a certain little lady really was awake at that time.
MC: …..
MC: Since you put it that way, Professor Xu… that means you weren't asleep either then.
Lucien: Oh, so you really have been awake the whole time too.
He leisurely draws out his sigh, making me feel even hotter. So I huff twice and deliberately purse my lips.
MC: If I had known it'd turn out like this, we might as well have chatted and tried to get sleepy together.
Lucien: Then I'm afraid we really would've ended up pulling an all-nighter.
MC: Why's that?
Lucien: After all, in moments like these, I always seem to have so much I want to say to you.
He speaks candidly, making me feel that no matter what he says, I won't be able to refuse.
MC: Then I'd only feel very happy.
Lucien: Can just this alone bring happiness?
MC: Of course, because I got to hear your heart.
I lead Lucien by the hand toward the lawn deep in the park, passing puddles at our feet and a tree strewn with fallen blossoms.
For a while, neither of us speaks, and my heart grows very quiet.
Then I hear Lucien speak.
Lucien: Actually, when it started raining before dawn, I felt uneasy, defeated, and dejected. Even…
Lucien: Anticipation.
His voice sounds softly, causing me to subconsciously soften my breathing as well.
Lucien: I can't help but think, perhaps my invitation was too sudden.
Lucien: I should have given it more thought, or rather, done some more preparation. At the very least, I should've checked the weather forecast before inviting you.
He shrugs his shoulders with a smile, and I follow suit, lifting the corners of my mouth. But his joking line inexplicably scratches at my heart, making it itch.
Lucien: Failure is the norm if one insists on advancing a difficult experiment under uncontrollable conditions.
Lucien: But unfortunately, cognition and choice are not always aligned.
Lucien: The thought that my impulsiveness might cause your expectation to come to nothing leaves me somewhat unwilling to accept it.
As he speaks with sincerity, I suddenly realize why the person lying beside me would be so silent when the rain poured like a torrent.
MC: Ah, people really are so different from one another.
MC: While Professor Xu reflected on himself when he couldn't sleep, I thought about nothing at all.
Hearing my exaggerated sigh, Lucien turns toward me with keen interest in his eyes.
Lucien: Weren't you worried?
MC: If I had to put it into words, later on I kept feeling like… none of it mattered.
MC: Whether it's a magical rainy-day kite that exceeded expectations, or the two of us waiting together for the clear skies to arrive.
MC: Maybe we'll make a promise for the next time the weather is nice, or maybe you'll take me somewhere even farther away, to a place full of sunshine. What words would you say to me then?
Lucien: "The world is a vast place—not everywhere is caught in rain."
I blink a few times, then laugh together with him.
MC: Professor Xu, have you 'rehearsed' this response too?
Lucien: I’m simply in the habit of preparing for all kinds of hypothetical scenarios.
MC: Then, did our Professor Xu spend the whole night rehearsing hypotheticals without sleeping properly?
Lucien: I fell asleep after the rain stopped, and I slept very well.
Lucien: Because what I had been anticipating happened.
MC: Was it the rain stopping?
Lucien: It was a miracle.
Lucien: After the rain, I began to anticipate a miracle.
Lucien: They heard how devout I was, so the whole world came to help.²²
As Lucien speaks these words, dappled light happens to leap onto his brows, the corners of his eyes, and the tips of his hair, making his eyes sparkle brightly.
Lucien: MC, right now I feel that today might just be our luckiest day of the year.
His brows and eyes curve with a smile, making no attempt to hide just how happy he is. Being gazed at like this by him, my eyes can’t help but grow hot.
MC: It's all my fault. I shouldn't have dragged you into those superstitious activities.
Lucien: That's right, you'll have to take responsibility.
As we speak, a vast lawn comes into view, emerald green spreading as far as the eye can reach, appearing supple under the sunlight.
Nameless little flowers dot the grass, and heaven and earth are condensed into dewdrops on the branches and leaves, like a world held in stillness.
It truly is good weather today.t truly is good weather today.
The only thing is that it's too still.
Lucien: …..
Lucien comes to a stop, his chest involuntarily rising and falling faintly.
Under the scorching sun, his repeated running causes him to sweat lightly, and his bared skin is also tinged with a faint flush from the heat.
Lucien: …I'll try again.
After finishing his words, he places the kite onto the grass, continuously tugging at the spool as he moves backward, then starts jogging again.
I promptly follow in his footsteps.
MC: Lucien, move a little to the left… no no—your left!
MC: …Wait, don't pull the string yet!
He follows each instruction, but the kite's clean paper surface only sweeps over the grass again and again, the pink ribbons tied to it like strands of fish lingering and swimming among the blades.
Yet it never once lifts from the ground.
After grazing past a few small flowers, it struggles on before eventually coming to rest in the grass.
Lucien stops once more, his back-turned figure somewhat silent.
He keeps his head lowered, his thoughts unreadable to me; the ribbon dangling from the kite quietly brushes his sleeve.
I instinctively quicken my steps in his direction. Only when I draw near do I realize his gaze rests intently on the kite.
His lowered lashes quiver faintly, as if in thought and as if listening to something.
Lucien: Just now, I confirmed the real-time wind speed, wind force, and air humidity.
Lucien: But…
He lets out a soft sigh, brows furrowed as he murmurs.
Lucien: Although the current wind force is insufficient to lift the kite, theoretically, my running speed should be adequate…
Lucien: Is the kite not light enough, or is its structure unstable?
As he speaks, his fingertips brush along the skeletal frame inch by inch. Lifting the kite slightly, he turns it toward the light to examine the paper surface closely.
Finally, he even takes out his phone's flashlight, shines it, and observes the kite's connection points with meticulous care, as if he is calibrating some precise laboratory apparatus.
I can't help but find him rather adorable, so I just stand quietly to the side, watching him study this 'flight apparatus'.
It turns out that this person really doesn't know how to fly a kite.
Lucien: MC, I know where the problem is.
I blink, waiting for him to go on.
Lucien: This kite has been stored away for too long.
Lucien: Even if properly stored, the paper surface will still show minor dampening and instability in its balance.
Lucien: Perhaps while holding it, I can adjust the angle a bit, tilting it about 8 degrees to the left.
MC: ….
Lucien: Let's try again.
Before I can open my mouth to stop him, he's already tugging the string and starting to run, his arm raised high.
After being launched, the kite sways unsteadily, floats for just a moment, then falls back onto the grass.
The string in his hand drops down. Lucien merely glances back once, then turns and sprints off again in another direction.
MC: ...Such a stubborn fool.
I no longer stop him, just watch with a smile as he keeps repeating the same motions.
Again and again, over and over, like walking on a track he is unfamiliar with and not in the least skilled at.
Unwearied by the trouble and tedium, vexed yet full of anticipation.
Until the fine sheen of sweat dampens his shirt, outlining his slender frame, and at last he stops.
From afar, Lucien gazes toward me.
Even though I cannot see him clearly against the light, I still seem to hear his voice.
So I spread my arms wide toward him.
He walks toward me step by step, and finally even breaks into a run.
I move forward to meet him, embracing him tightly in my arms.
MC: Fool.
Scent of rain-drenched grass wraps around me, welling in my eyes and seeping into my heart, moistening them both.²³
The head resting atop mine gives a slight nod, as if in acknowledgment.
MC: Let's rest for a while.²⁴
A muffled reply falls. Lucien releases me and lies down on the grass.
The unwound kite string loosely encircles him, wrapping him into a colorful and tender embrace.
Soft strands of his hair are brushed aside by the breeze, revealing a pair of eyes uncharacteristically at a loss.
Perhaps even vast and intricate experimental data will not deter him; yet, at this moment, a kite trips up the genius's steps, causing him to inadvertently reveal a flicker of childlike vulnerability.
He tilts his head up to look at me, gently closes his eyes for a moment, and lets out a sigh as if defeated.
Lucien: Teacher, I am a slow student.²⁵
Lucien: I can't even learn something this simple.
MC: Who says this is simple?
I refute him without hesitation, making those beautiful eyes widen momentarily.
I can't help but feel my heart soften. I crouch down over him, cup my chin, and look at him carefully.
MC: It's complicated.
MC: It needs patience, it requires skill, and it also needs the ability to observe and weigh things thoughtfully.
MC: It even requires just that little bit of extra luck.
A few flower stems cast faint, swaying shadows on his face, making him lower his lashes as if to escape.
The kite is loosely held in his hand, one corner drifting up lightly with the wind, then pulled down by him again, like a heart restlessly eager yet unwilling to yield.
I gently hold the kite string, which hangs down at his side, watching it wind and coil between us, like gazing down at a small river flowing through one another.
MC: Bond and freedom are inherently contradictory. It’s difficult to strike a balance, isn’t it?²⁶
Wind on the ground billows the thin, light clothing. I look up toward the source of the 'small river', only to meet Lucien's thoughtful gaze directly.
Lucien: Yeah, it’s difficult.
Lucien: Seems like in moments like these, I'm always somewhat flustered and a little clumsy.
MC: Do you not want me to see?
Lucien: No, that's not it.
Lucien: I'm glad you saw all of this.
Lucien: It’s just that I can’t help but wonder if the one pulling the thread was you… Then maybe this matter wouldn’t be so complicated.
His fingertips tap, seemingly inadvertently, on the spool handle before they tentatively reach toward me.
He's talking about flying a kite, yet it's not just about flying a kite.
MC: But I can't do it alone.²⁷
Smiling, I shake my head at him, leaving him stunned for a moment.
MC: This is our promise; only when we fulfill it together does it hold meaning.
MC: Lucien, I can't do it alone.
MC: Just like love, this is a matter of two people.
Cicadas' cries drift from afar, and sunlight bathes the world, exposing its colors into richer, more variegated hues.
Lucien: MC, on one hand, I want to let you lead all of this, but on the other, I can't help wanting to do a lot alone.
Lucien: Is this also love?
MC: Perhaps it is.
Lucien: Then I feel fortunate, so deeply fortunate, that the person standing before me at this moment is you.
Lucien: Is this also love?
MC: Perhaps it is, too.
He blinks, his beautiful eyes suffused with a moist, glistening light. In that instant, the grass, trees, and flowers around him seemed to fade in color.²⁸
Letting me gladly and willingly drown in their depths.
Lucien: MC, please keep teaching me more.²⁹
Until that hazy warmth and loneliness gain clearer contours, until my cowardice always grows alongside my love.
Until I no longer need deduction or imitation, converging all this into love's own language.
I can't resist lowering my head and kissing him.
²²: 祂 (tā) is a special pronoun used mainly in religious or spiritual contexts to refer to God or divine being(s), distinguishing it from 他 (he), 她 (she), or 它 (it).
I use They in English to carry that same sense of reverence while also leaving room for the possibility that the text is speaking of more than one god or divine presence, after all, he used it to refer to how the whole world came to help~
²³: Random fun fact is that Lucien is often described with the scent of grass… so when the smell wraps around her, it's also a poetic way of saying he's embracing her. Yet it's also a wet scent that carries emotional weight of his endearing yet distressing stubbornness, seeping into her eyes and heart, making her tears rise and her heart ache.
MC asks Lucien to rest instantly make me recalls last year’s summer SP (The Sea No Longer Far Away/Seaside At Last SP) As I mentioned in my previous Translation Notes and Insight, the Summer SP was where they learned to give each other the signal that it's okay to rest.
But reaching that point took a journey: before then, Lucien literally tried to put into practice her metaphor of what it felt like to follow in his footsteps, doing something unfamiliar, failing over and over to the sea, and starting again, just to understand her feelings.
That same stubborn fool is now facing another unfamiliar challenge, once again failing again and again and tirelessly starting over each time to fulfill their promise ;-;
And here, when Lucien looks at MC and she opens her arms wide, it mirrors the 7th Anniversary, except this time it's not her running into his arms… It's him running into hers, caught in her tight embrace.
It's an act of finding and giving mutual solace, of complete acceptance, and of their growth as she also understands the importance of giving him the signal to rest.
This date is absolutely INSANE as the culmination of nearly eight years of their relationship growth.
²⁵: 笨学生 (bèn xué shēng) is often translated as 'stupid student', but in this context, it leans more to a humble 'I struggle to grasp this despite effort.' An idiomatic English equivalent for 笨学生 might be 'slow learner'.
However, I’ve chosen a slow student to retain the 'student' element, which preserves his deferential tone toward his 'teacher'. Other possible translations are foolish student or clumsy student, but neither foolish nor clumsy quite captures the meaning of 笨 here
Lucien flying a kite without wind might be foolish, and his not smooth attempts might be clumsy, but what's being conveyed is his genuine struggle to learn despite his efforts.
²⁶: I've translated this word into bond, but it might not capture the implicit restriction (hence the contradiction with freedom). The term 牵绊 (qiān bàn) is central to understanding this tension, as it refers to the emotional ties that bind people together, such as love, family, or deep friendship.
These bonds offer support, connection, and meaning, but they also imply being held back, obligated, or constrained. The character 牵 (qiān) means to pull or involve, while 绊 (bàn) means to trip or hinder.
In the metaphor of flying a kite, the string is the 牵绊: it's what allows the kite to rise, guided and connected, but also what holds it back from complete freedom. Lucien lying down while being tenderly embraced by the kite string, and the string being held by MC like she's the one anchoring him to the world, making him stand on solid ground…
I think the image beautifully encapsulates the essence of 牵绊. And indeed, balancing both 牵绊 (bond/tie) and ⾃由 (freedom) is never easy.
²⁷: The way they transform his infamous 'joking' line from chapter 13 where our Great Professor Lucien, with that aggrieved little expression, goes "I can't do it alone / won't be alright alone" when she said she wants to investigate by herself-
-into something so solemn here, of love as not something one should carry alone, but something to be fulfilled and shoulder together… LUCIEN WRITERS YOUR MIND!!!
The whole scene is such a masterstroke too! Lucien, who is still wrestling with the contradictory nature of love, is trying to make sense of it all. How he wants to let her lead, b/c a part of him believes maybe things wouldn't be so messy if only she bore the emotional reins, only for her to say that "I can't do it alone" b/c love isn’t a one-person task.
Then he wonders, if I still want to bear things alone sometimes, is that also love? And MC doesn't deny him, simply saying, "Perhaps it is." And that's when he says he feels fortunate, so deeply fortunate that the person standing before him is someone who understands him, his contradictions, his inner wars, and loves him as he is.
²⁸: In CN 眼眸覆上盈润的光 (lit. "eyes covered with moist light") often suggests eyes welling with unshed tears or an intense emotional sheen (tenderness, vulnerability, etc.). That raw radiance in his gaze is so vivid it seems to strip the surrounding world of its own colors 🥺
²⁹: "MC, please keep teaching me more." I think every XM stan knows just how precious these words are without me needing to overexplain. A genius, yet he's willing to be your most devoted, 'slow' student, stumbling and falling again and again in an effort to learn how to love you🥹 It's hard to not be touched...
The sky is seamless and blue, as if it has been washed clean, with a few wisps of cloud fluff floating by. Tender shoots of green grass brush the back of my neck and the rims of my ears, bringing a warm, ticklish sensation.
Sunlight spills down, blooming into a rainbow halo in my vision; I can't help but lazily lift a hand to shade my eyes.
Lucien and I lie head-to-head on the grass, the earth beneath us sending up faint tremors, as if enfolding us within the world's breathing.
Following my example, Lucien also stretches out his arm. His fingertips gently hook mine, and his low voice tickles in close, spilling out a trace of amusement.
Lucien: Is this now the second step of our kite-flying lesson?
MC: ...This student, please refrain from questioning your teacher.
MC: Proper rest and adjustment are indeed an essential step in the learning process!
Lucien: Hm, Teacher is right.
MC: [the way his expression suddenly turns cunning as she cluelessly says this LOL] But why is it the second step?
Before the words have even left my lips, the man beside me rises and leans in, those long, narrow eyes glinting with triumph.
The next moment, a warmth wrapped in the scent of fresh grass falls upon my lips.
His loosened bangs brush against my eyelids, lightly tickling, yet I can't bear to close them.
After pulling back slightly, I mutter with feigned sternness.
MC: Student, you're sneakily switching concepts!
Lucien: Is that so? I thought it was called 'applying what I learned to master it'.
MC: Your eagerness to learn is really strong right now, isn't it.
Lucien: After all, you've already taught me so much in this course. It's only right that I work harder.
He speaks frankly, and there's indeed an air of humble eagerness to learn in his demeanor.
I roll onto my side to face him, resting my head on my arm as I gaze at him earnestly.
Sunshine falls behind him, framing the kite he still cradles in his hands in a soft halo of light.
It clearly hasn't moved, but it seems as if it has already taken flight.
I have imagined this very scene so many times and daydreamed about the us of now. It feels different, yet somehow not so different.
I can't help reaching out to lay my hand over his chest, as if this simple act alone could touch that heart laid open to me.
MC: Do you know what we’re learning right now?
Lucien shakes his head.
MC: We're learning to get accustomed and to wait.
He doesn't say a word, only looks at me deeply.
MC: When it started raining early this morning... I did feel a little disheartened. But strangely enough, I wasn't really surprised.
MC: Perhaps it's because when it comes to flying a kite, all kinds of unexpected things always come with it, like a test left to us by fate.
MC: Or perhaps it's that we both hope the day this promise is fulfilled will be special enough, so we never bring it up lightly.
MC: I wonder if we have bestowed far too much upon it, so much so that it grows heavier and heavier.
MC: As time passes, I seem to have grown accustomed to its 'postponement', yet remain utterly certain it will arrive in the end, and so waiting has become second nature.
His gaze on me wavers ever so slightly, and I vaguely sense the pulsation beneath my fingertips unintentionally quicken.
Lucien: Why didn't you bring this up before?
His voice is soft, yet it makes me fall briefly silent.
Yeah. Why didn't I take the initiative to bring this up before?
It was clearly a promise belonging to both of us. Clearly, either of us could have taken the first step.
Maybe it is because it's too special.
In that stretch of bittersweet memory, I don't know whether I should solemnly take it up or naturally hold it tight just then.
Should my tone be calm and even, or should I reveal an expression of wholehearted joy?
So whenever I think of this matter, I always feel a bit hesitant. It's because it is too deeply treasured that it's approached so cautiously.
And so, just like that, year after year, it follows us forward, watching us change and grow.
Like a shadow that accompanies us, it becomes part of us.
Even now, I find no fitting reason to explain it.
Lucien: Because I used to be afraid.³⁰
Lucien suddenly speaks, answering the very question he asked me.
He lifts his hand and catches my fingertips, gently tightening his hold.
Lucien: When I'm far away from you, the deeper my love for you grows. The closer I am to you, the more I feel I'm still not enough.³¹
Lucien: Not honest enough, not courageous enough…
Lucien: Not real enough.
He says while raising that kite.
The snow-white paper surface is now stained with a slight muddiness; the pink ribbons bound to it flutter as if whispering something.
When I saw it placed with care in the entryway before we left, I knew then that this was not a hastily prepared kite.
Yet I had absolutely no idea when it had already been in our home.
As if he has seen through my heart, Lucien's gaze also falls toward the kite.
Lucien: I probably prepared it a long time ago and recorded many moments.
Lucien: Every time I felt I was one step closer to completing this, I would tie a knot on this kite.³²
As he speaks, the ribbons happen to flutter up, their refracted colors streaming into my eyes, making them grow slightly warm.
Lucien: They are both my honesty and courage, and also my hesitation and wavering.
Lucien: It's like an unsolved equation. Before a new answer emerges, it reappears time and again, compelling me to explore it over and over.
Lucien: It makes me confront it all the time and reflect on it again and again.
Lucien: But MC, I've never forgotten this promise.
His eyes unhurriedly settle back on me.
Lucien: In fact, there were many moments in the past when I would often think of it.
Lucien: And whenever I think of it, I distinctly feel a kind of change.
Lucien: One that feels like roots taking hold and buds sprouting.
Lucien: It spreads bit by bit, until it fills my entire heart, until it bursts forth in vigorous growth.³³
My fingertips, guided by him, wander across his chest, as if sketching the scene he described.
Scorching pulses pass through his skin into mine, and my heart resonates in response.
For the moment, I don’t know what to say; I can only try hard to slow my breathing, afraid that the scene before my eyes will become blurry in the blink of an eye.
Lucien: This feeling makes me happy and satisfied, yet I greedily want to keep it all to myself.
Lucien: So it turns out I'm this much of a cowardly and selfish person.
The world becomes a hazy wash of brilliant colors. I lean in, eyes shut, and press a kiss against his eyes.
MC: Fool.
MC: You've already come to be completely certain that, no matter how cruelly you dissect yourself, I can accept all of it.³⁴
MC: How can you still call yourself cowardly when you're so certain and confident?
MC: Obviously it's me who doesn't know what to do with you.
Lucien: Then just always worry about me.³⁵
Lucien: Before you teach me more, I hope I can become the subject you will forever study and explore.
The soft pads of his fingers brush affectionately past the corner of my eye, then cradle my face with utmost care.
At this very moment, my heart and eyes are wholly filled with him. In his gaze, I can distinctly see my complete self, the vast sky, and the swaying flowers, grasses, and trees.
I suddenly realize something and immediately pull Lucien to a sitting position.
MC: Lucien—
Lucien: The wind is rising.³⁶
We run on the grass like two children, holding onto the string, tugging and pulling it together—
The kite finally soars into the sky.
It rides the wind, passing through my countless imaginings and anticipations, glides past light and shadow, and comes to rest in the azure sky.
Its edges are both vague and clear. It appears so simple, yet also seems so surreal.
I feel as if I’m also being gently lifted, like that tiny kite, but I can only see with blurry vision.
When the kite flies up into the sky, Lucien feels that he has seen such a scene before.
Through the long years after the promise was sealed with a pinky swear, he has seen it in his dreams.
But the teardrop that slips unbidden from the corner of the girl's eye, rolling onto his fingertips as she smiles, is something he has never seen in those dreams.
Scalding and profoundly heavy, it seeps its way into his heart, filling him with a sense of fulfilled wholeness and making him feel at peace.
Lucien: ...Don't cry.
His warm fingertip brushes over my eyes, letting them trace his outline again and again.
Lucien: MC, the weather is very good today— even if it isn't spring, it's still very good.
Lucien: And I... have walked step by step until I arrived before you.
Lucien: Our kite has flown up.
It is as if he, too, is now struggling for words, no longer able to find any phrasing that can fully articulate or thoroughly explain this distant and drawn-out road.
So he can only tighten his arms. His kiss replaces his fingertips, replaces words, replaces everything.
This kiss is far too tender and reverent. I close my eyes, yet it’s as if I see his countless countenances.
Gentle, indifferent, sad, aggrieved, smiling… until at last, they all merge into the face of the person before me.
Just like his kiss, obviously so endearingly moving, yet in the moment of my instinctual retreat, it assertively pulls me back to his side.³⁷
I’m deeply entangled in him—no longer able to escape, unable to leave.
I open my eyes and fall into those serene, profound pupils, seeing all the solemn sincerity and love within them.
MC: I…..
Lucien: I love you, MC.
Lucien: I love you.
He draws closer to me; there is no longer any hesitation or doubt in him.
Lucien: Even if I still haven't understood the full meaning of love, even if I am such a slow student of yours.
Lucien: But in this moment, I know… I love you.
He repeats tirelessly, yet each utterance is so different.
Love is such a simple and yet complex feeling. At this moment, I realize it cannot be assisted or replaced by any words.
Whenever it is mentioned, I can see Lucien and myself on this long, long road.
MC: Then do you know my answer?
Lucien: I know.
Lucien: Because... I've felt love.
He gently lifts the corners of his mouth and simply gazes at me quietly, as if gazing upward in reverence.
I cup his face in my hands, trying to see him more clearly.
MC: Lucien, I love you.
We don't let such beautiful and gentle weather go to waste.
It’s just perfect how the kite string loops around the ring finger of his left hand once their promise is finally fulfilled... because that's exactly where a wedding ring is traditionally worn by the groom;-;
Coincidental, as if the world itself is acknowledging his commitment; with MC is the one holding the string, the one tethering him, grounding him, but also letting him fly—she becomes both his restraint and his freedom.
³⁰: Remember what I said in the date guide about the 7th anniversary being full of Chekhov's guns? Here's another one firing! In the 7th anniversary story, Lucien teasingly asks the MC if she wants to hear him say "I'm afraid" (害怕 / hàipà), and she shoots back, asking if there was anything else he didn't dare do.
Now he finally says it in earnest: "因为我曾经害怕" (Yīnwèi wǒ céngjīng hàipà / "Because I used to be afraid"). And some of those fears, the things he never dared to do before… this whole story becomes his answer ;-;
³¹: When he's far from you, the deeper his love for you grows; yet when he draws close, he's afraid he's not enough to show just how deeply he loves you. It’s not that his love is not enough or falls short, but that he doubts his own ability to love and even himself. Afraid that he's not honest enough, not brave enough, not… real enough.
That last line with its use of 真实 (zhēn shí, genuine, not fake (authentic), and also factually consistent with reality (real/existing)) is striking because on one level it’s a callback to the 7th anniversary when he confessed that she’s what makes him real and be his authentic self, allowing him to continue 'existing'.
But it can also be read as him breaking the fourth wall, feeling afraid that he's not real enough for us.
³²: This is our eighth year together, and if you see the full art of the pre-evolve CG, there are exactly eight ribbons tied to the kite in the CG… Has it really been here all this time, ever since he made that promise? Even after everything that happened at chapter 13, did he still choose to immediately buy it, holding on to the hope that they’ll really fly one someday?
I can’t help but wonder, when Lucien bought the new kite again in Season 2, did he quietly add the ribbons from his Season 1 memories after getting his memories back? Turns out this kite has been silently accompanying them through all the years, bearing witness as their love quietly grew for eight long years….
Perhaps buying a kite is easy; what's difficult is finding the courage to fulfill that promise, the courage to choose to love someone even when you know it won't be perfect or 'fitting', when love is complicated and can be nearly impossible to express in its entirety.
Maybe that’s why the old kite itself is so precious. Each ribbon marks a step in his long, hesitant journey toward being ready and certain to love; it records and treasures the messy process, showing that it’s precisely this imperfect, human becoming that makes love real.
³³: Lucien and MC's narrative progression with the plant-growth metaphor is honestly a stroke of genius🥹—
what begins as a seed (the heart-throbbing/infatuation, bringing instinctive joy and happiness, fulfill their desires)
gradually grows and bears flowers (love itself, something more profound and more enduring than fleeting happiness or a fluttering heart,
where the beloved’s happiness becomes more important than satisfying one's own desires),
and from there, love also gives rise to other human emotions intertwined with it (pain, fear, greed, hesitation, but also satisfaction, courage, persistence and tenderness) ultimately taking root and sprouting buds (signifying both vitality and anchoring, something that continually renews itself and turn their bond to be a lifelong one).
So love for them isn't just something fleeting, but about love evolving through stages, becoming more complex, fertile, and enduring over time.
Also! The recurring theme of words is inadequate when it comes to expressing the depths of love. Instead, feelings are conveyed through the body, through touch, through heartbeat.
For someone who usually relies on intellect and speech, Lucien's choice to abandon words and let his heart speak reveals both vulnerability, growth, and the rawness of his emotions. It shows his recognition that the heart can express truth more honestly than any rhetoric ever could.
³⁴: 你已经完全确认,无论你对自己进行多么残忍的剖析,我都能接受了 (You’ve already come to be completely certain/fully confirmed that, no matter how cruelly you dissect yourself, I can accept all of it.) is an echo of the 7th Anniversary, where he does become certain that no matter how ruthlessly he analyzes himself, or what choices he makes,
she will always choose to walk toward him and embrace everything that he is. She isn’t trying to fix him, nor is she afraid of the darker or more complicated parts of who he is. Instead, she shows a mature, steady kind of love—the kind that fully sees someone, flaws and all, and stays anyway.
³⁵: I translated it as worry, but in a romantic context, 烦恼 (fán nǎo) implies a deeper, more persistent state of thoughtful preoccupation and tender concern. It's not the usual "I'm scared something bad will happen" kind of worry (that would be 担心 dān xīn)
as it’s more of a kind of soft, constant emotional entanglement where someone lives in your head and in your heart rent-free. That line as a whole is a vulnerable and slightly possessive confession, like he's asking her to never stop caring, overthinking, loving, and being tenderly troubled by him and his complexities.
³⁶: 起风了 (The wind is rising) is the same line from their VERY FIRST date, firefly date. The contrast in how Lucien feels each time he says it, as well as the progression of their relationship, is just so ༼;´༎ຶ ۝ ༎ຶ༽.
The repetition of 'The wind is rising' bridges the beginning of their story to this moment, showing just how far Lucien has grown through his connection with her.
In the Firefly date, he uses the line to reference the French poem "The Graveyard by the Sea" by Paul Valéry. Back then, seeing the weak fireflies made him think they won’t live long because survival of the fittest is all he’s ever known.
But earlier in this MQ, when he sees the fireflies glowing around them, he doesn’t see survival – he sees wonder, through her smile and joy, through the fireflies' glow in her eyes.
From once viewing the world through a detached, almost fatalistic lens, to now holding onto beauty and learning how to cherish it, he’s no longer just surviving and observing life. He's living it. Because of her. Because of love.
³⁷: 惹人爱怜 (rě rén ài lián, lit - 'causes people to feel pity and love/affection’). It describes someone/something so endearing that you can't help but want to love and protect them. I like how this phrase is used in this context; it highlights the tender, vulnerable quality of his kiss while contrasting with the firm assertiveness that keeps her from retreating.
It also reminds me of his prison AU number 0525 (ling wǔ èr wǔ), which can be read as "怜我爱我" (lián wǒ ài wǒ), literally meaning 'pity me, love me'.
Seven years is a long time. Long enough that I started to wonder if maybe they'd never fly that kite. That perhaps it was something meant to stay unfinished until they reach their happy ending at the end of the game. But looking back now, I think it was just a matter of waiting for spring to arrive.
Just like he once said back in Season 2 Chapter 13, "Spring isn't necessarily just a fixed time.", maybe it's not spring as in the season but the spring in his heart. It took him years to reach this point. Through the 7th anniversary, when he revealed the black-and-white world and the colors she brought to it, when he confessed how love had brought him fear and courage,
pain and comfort, and ultimately, a sense of being real. Through Because of Love, when he finally let go of hesitation and bared his entire heart without any reservation. Only after all of that could the kite finally rise.
And maybe it's perfect that it happens in summer, because it's a season full of rainy days, where on some days they have to chase after the miracle of a 20% chance of sunshine, just like the kite, something they'd been trying to fly for years, always held back by timing, circumstance, and its heavy meaning.
It emphasizes the struggle and the long road they took to finally make it fly, making the moment it soars feel like something far more than a simple scene. It's the culmination of everything he had endured: his insecurity, his fear, his yearning, his pain.
He had to walk a long and difficult path before he could finally stand before her with frankness, look into her eyes, and say, "I love you. My heart chooses to love you." (Because of Love after-evolve karma's line)
Of course, even after he found the courage to ask her to fly one, actually flying the kite wasn't easy. He kept running back and forth, as if sheer effort could replace the missing wind. She called out directions, and he followed, but you could still see that he was trying to shoulder everything by himself, continually adjusting the kite experimentally.
Watching this genius fumble so earnestly, my tears wouldn't stop. Such a fool, unwilling to give up, reluctant to lean on anyone. It wasn't until she signaled him to rest that he lay back in the grass, the string falling loosely around him like a soft embrace, and whispered, "Teacher, I am a slow student." And that was the moment he turned to her.
Not just about the kite, but about the two of them. Admitting his vulnerability, letting her in, allowing himself to be guided… because only when you show all of yourself can you be thoroughly cherished and loved, right? And she answered with the same sentence he said years ago: "But I can't do it alone."
And that's it, isn't it? Love isn't a solo endeavor. Neither is fulfilling a promise to fly a kite. Honestly, the kite is such a brilliant metaphor for love itself: it needs effort, patience, timing, a little luck, and the delicate balance between restraint and freedom.
And one of the things I love most about XMMC's love is that it's a bond built from nothing, where looking back, you can trace every step as they grow together. Maybe the yearning was light at first, just curiosity toward someone who could have remained a stranger.
But over the years, it grew heavier because their bond was something they had to choose and rebuild again and again, despite fear, hesitation, and obstacles. Their whole story is a reminder of how fragile and miraculous love can be.
Luck gave them the chance to meet, but it was their choices that kept it alive. The yearning never ends because every moment of happiness carries the awareness that it all could have slipped away, and the only way to honor that miracle is to hold on tightly and protect it with everything you are.
Once they opened their hearts to each other again and stopped hiding, revealing the reason why it took so long to fulfill this promise, the wind began to blow.
The kite soared as they held the string together. Beneath it, he said "Don't cry" with such gentleness (which actually makes me cry even harder ༼;' ༎ຶ ۝ ༎ຶ༽), kissing again and again, repeatedly whispering "I love you" under the sky we all had waited years for.
Because in the end, there were no other words that could capture this long, arduous journey better than love. That day wasn't just a sunny day. It was a day filled with all the love they had fought so hard to understand.
Seven years of waiting. Seven years of growth. And finally, this promise was fulfilled.
From kites to fireflies, from red ribbons to red threads and even kite threads, from luck and miracles to love that's like a seed—love that makes people greedy, love that makes people afraid—so many things about this date instantly make me think of the long road we’ve walked together.
I could go on forever, but I'll stop here. If you've made it this far, thank you so much for reading. This story means the world to me, and I can't put into words how much it means to finally see this moment come true after everything.
Lucien, happy inner spring. Our kite has flown 🪁